Hello there
good morning, good afternoon, good evening
Welcome to my channel
thewanderingman abroad
Aseem Bhardwaj
Your host and friend
this is an updated Singapore video on
we are going to discuss travel requirements
step-by-step
because the last video I did
I just shared an update
that VTL has been removed
and starting April 01, there would be no VTL
The vaccinated travel framework will replace
VTL
This means no quarantine and not many restrictions
so let's talk in this video
so firstly I start with
it is for those who want to visit for short-term
visits
and also inquire about visas
so the short-term visitors must have basic
travel documents ready
for instance, a passport and you need a visa
I am going to discuss the visa requirements
further
but what do you need to do?
you have to get the covid-19 test done that
must be valid for 48 hours
2 days means 48 hours right?
you need that
then you need a travel insurance
and the minimum coverage must be SGD $30000
and there is no rule if you need to buy a
local travel insurance
but if you still need local insurance then
I can tell you that there are three major
companies out there
AIG Singapore
the second one is CHUBB travel insurance
and the third one is CHANGI FOR SURE
the cheapest out of these is CHANGI FOR SURE
ok
so we have talked about travel insurance
you can also get local ICICI Lombard and TATA
AIG
OR you can get Singapore's local travel insurance
and I have shown you on the screen
so now, you have to keep your vaccinated certificate
in hand
whatever documents I am discussing you need
physical copies
of these
let me clear this
you have to fill now a health declaration
form 72 hours before
which is called SG ARRIVAL CARD
I think this is clear, I hope everybody knows
it
so if you do not know, you have to health
declaration in the SG ARRIVAL CARD, 72 hours
before your departure
ok
so when we talk about immigration
actually, what happens
so when you fill this SG ARRIVAL CARD
you are issued an E-PASS
through your registered email
ok
and if you do not fill the SG ARRIVAL CARD
then you have to manually submit all the documents
to the immigration officer
so if you want to avoid the lengthy process,
queues
then the process is very simple you do register
on the SG ARRIVAL CARD
and you will get the proof on the email
because as now, the update I have got to know
and according to my knowledge
there is no stamping on your passport
they are only checking SG ARRIVAL CARD
whether someone has filled or not
ok
so that was about the SG ARRIVAL CARD
and then you have to download their contact
tracing app
that is known as the TRACE TOGETHER APP
if you are found positive in the last 7-90
days
that before your departure
so firstly, you need to check your eligibility
criteria
and I am going to share a link
in which.
you put vaccine information
when did you get infected
so do see that link once
so if you are eligible only then you plan
your trip
if you recently got infected with covid between
7-90 days
ok is that clear?
if you are symptomatic upon arrival
then you might have to go through an antigen
test or PCR test
and now the cost of antigen test is SGD $30
& the cost of PCR test is SGD $138
let me talk further, without wasting time-
about visas
Original Passport with at least 6 months'
validity
if that is less, then I cant help
you can apply but you may waste your money,
time, and efforts
so 6 months' validity is important
you need to fill out a visa application form
you can apply through Make my Trip, Akbar
travel
I had a word with Akbar travels
so you can submit your documents to them
and you can apply for a visa through them
very easily
sorry not sticker, it is known as E-visa
and you need to apply through a travel agent
So you can confirm through Make my trip, Akbar
travels, and Musafir
but I spoke to Akbar travels
you need 2 colored photographs
you might have to attach a covering letter
I had deposited a covering letter
and bank statement for the last 6 months
along with return flight tickets and hotel
reservations
now I talk about people who are traveling
apart from short-term visitors
who is going on Work Permit In-principle Approval
holders
non-Malaysian work permit holders
employed in the Construction, Marine shipyard,
and Process Sector (CMP worker)
the need to Apply for Entry Approval
otherwise, no approval is required in the
case of short-term visitors
but in the case of Malaysian work permit holders,
they need an entry approval from the Ministry
of Manpower at least 3 working days, a week
before, or 20 days whatever is convenient
for you- before the intended date of departure
so If I talk a bit about long term pass holders
Long-term pass and in-principle approval (IPA)
holders
Travelers should have a valid passcard or
IPA letter which will be shown during pre-boarding
checks or on arrival
ok
so this is about long term pass holders
so in this video, we talk about short-term
visitors
for fun for leisure
and we talked a bit about workers, long term
pass holders
what they need to do
ok
I hope this video is insightful
this is another small video on the Singapore
updated travel requirements
as I committed to you earlier
so I have done a video for you
do not forget to support the channel
do subscribe
and do like the video
ok
I see you in the next video
take very good care of yourselves
goodbye